<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Blattenberger B.LOG()</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://sean-blattenbegrer.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sean-blattenbegrer.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 13:16:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 13:16:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Back to Bootcamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ahhN0ET.jpg/1240x680&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t believe it’s been almost seven years since I “shipped” out to Navy bootcamp. It was no joy ride, that’s for sure. I knew the navy wasn’t the place for me but I knew what I’d gain far outweighed the inconvience of military life. I thought I’d never make it through and I honestly don’t think I would have without such amazing family and friends.  Thank you for all of your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-bootcamp&quot;&gt;Why bootcamp?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have my gripes with the buerocracy that is government service, I’d being lying if I said the military didn’t do a few things right. Bootcamp for example. An eight-week crash course designed to make you a sailor / soldier / marine / airman, whether you like it or not. It breaks you down so you can be rebuilt. You may not come out of it a navy seal but the tranformation that happens in such a short time is nothing short of amazing. As you all know, I also had the unique opportunity to learn Arabic right after bootcamp. 64 weeks of immersive insturction designed to take you from knowing nothing to being a highly-proficient linguist. I was confident I could survive bootcamp but I had my doubts about learning an entire language in a year and a half. Long story short, I made it thorugh and I did pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FAfq1y9.jpg/480x480&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, it was difficult but learning anything is difficult. So why did I feel so much better, so much more confident about my skills after this class then I did after a highschool class. Could it really just be that this course was MORE difficult. I don’t believe so. The easist class can be made difficult by a person who is willing to push themselves and set their own standards. What made my navy classes different, and in my opinion better, was the end goal. In highschool or college, they are rounding out students, making them competent in many things. In the military, time is of the essence. They need you to ‘useful’ sooner than latter. This is why military courses are structured to ‘sharpen’ their students. Mastery is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want a course that is going to sharpen my skills.  I’d rather be good at one thing than just ‘okay’ at a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-coding-bootcamp&quot;&gt;What’s coding bootcamp?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/DyrEDZZ.jpg/930x420&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot; data-lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Quote&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;skilledup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Coding bootcamps are months-long&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;intensive experiences. Each day offers&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;new challenges. Most bootcamps require&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;a full-time commitment, but there are&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;a lot of part-time programs and remote&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;options emerging. This new format of&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;learning to code is efficiently producing&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;employable graduates.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I ship out again to attend another bootcamp, a coding bootcamp at Coding House Institute. It’s a fully immersive, 8-week course. The only live in bootcamp, it aims to eliminate every possible distraction. No cooking, no commute - just live, eat, and code. I’m grateful to have this opportunity and am excited to learn a new, valuable skillset.  There’s so much to learn in such a short time. I’m nervous but I know what can be accomplished when you immerse yourself in a subject. Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sean-blattenbegrer.github.io/blog/back-to-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sean-blattenbegrer.github.io/blog/back-to-work/</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
